Prajeet: Hello everyone,  this is Prajeet Shrestha
back with another video where we will
discuss a research project that we were
quite working on for a while now
now this is something that was really
important for us not because it was a
semester assessment but it was something
that we really wanted to work on
and be able to produce a significant
the result I have my team members with me to
discuss about the project and just to
touch on everything that we did
however if you want to learn more about
the project in detail you can email me
to get the research paper which will be
released after first of December
Saahil: Thank you so much for inviting us
Prajeet: Welcome everyone now talking
about the project like i said it is a
research-based project for developing a
user interface from the perspective of
HCI for a self-driving car simulator
now carla is an open source simulator
where you can Simulate and research on
self-driving cars in this space i would
like to create an opportunity for us to
discuss the journey that we do before we
discuss anything
let's just understand some of the
objectives of the project from Aayush,
Aayush: Thank you so much Prajeet for the lovely
introduction of the project I'm Aayush Kafle
I'm here to talk about the Objectives
that we're trying to reach while creating
this interface design
before that i would like to explain why
we created this ui design in the first
place
now in our system to do the simple
things inside of simulation
we need to manually call the function
like when we record a simulation or
start it it's more like cui
so we decided to create a smart UI to
make our task easier
in terms of adding or changing things
and simulation so that
programmer can focus on the actual part of the
research now the objectives we tried to
reach while creating this interface was
to create a control panel or system ui
for better Usability
To create a consistent UI that followed
most of the UI principles
and to cater to the universality of the
user's product
and finally we try to justify the
objectives and statements with the
survey
where we found that 75 percent of people
in this relevant research
work yeah so keeping those in mind
during the second week
we created a case document and had an
open discussion with some of our
colleague team
where we found the pros and cons of the
project and improvised and
pre-documented it
which was a huge milestone for us in
terms of improvement
and once we had a proper idea and
supporting document on our third week
we started working on creating a paper
prototype the model that you see here
was the final prototype that we created
with a lot of suggestions and feedback
from people about what they liked and
disliked
you can find more about the prototype in
our resource paper
as we moved on to the next week what we
had to do was to create a ui that users
can interact with
so we created a front-end interface with
javascript and html
css it took us almost a week to finalize
the interface
but once we completed it it was
something we really liked
and loved the design of the interface
the ui that you are looking at
is what we developed after working on it
for a week and we're quite happy about
it
as we progressed on to the next phase of
our research we invited a few of our
colleagues to evaluate and concern the
design
and identify as many potential usability
problems
as possible now this space was really
crucial for us because
it would give us an external perspective
and opportunity for improvement
heuristic evaluation was done based on
jacob's nielsen
10 usability heuristics for finding any
design issues associated with the user
interface
so finally what we needed to find was
how users with different background and
knowledge would
observe and react to our ui so we
created a user persona of other type of
users that might use a product some of
them were like
a fourth-year student researching on
self-driving car in different weathers
or a graduate student trying to record
and analyze the algorithm we conducted
those kinds of ethnographic  resource for
those users who understand how a certain
group of customers would interact and
observe the ui for any case we also
produce a detailed summarization of each
principles
used and evaluated the UI based on
Schneiderman’s 8 Golden Rules
as well as Norman's 7 principles for better
understanding of the product and
improvising it
and now what we needed to do was to see
how user-friendly the UI is so we
conducted some of the online phone
usability testing
in google meet to let some user actually
experience the
ui and give us some feedbacks and we
reported the whole
interview and produced some conclusion
like the heat map that you can see here
and that's how we completed and
concluded the research project. I would
like to thank you Mr.Sushil Shrestha for
giving us this opportunity and the whole
team for everything that they did thank
you stay safe bye